Guide to the Papers of Harrison Salisbury,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Box Listing (unsorted)
  - The Unknown War: Miscellaneous pages out of order, many w/corrections -- Multiple copies or versions of some pp (Box 313, Folder 7)
  - The Unknown War: 3 large-scale soviet maps (in Russian) of WWII battle areas (Box 313, Folder 8)
  - The Unknown War: Photocopy from book in Russian (Box 313, Folder 9)
  - The Unkown War: Complete mss. duplicates of Chapters 1 and 2, and a few other pp. See also folders 3-7, above. (Box 313, Folder 10)
  - Travels Around America: Proofs from Esquire, book mss. (196 pp.) (Box 314, Folder 11)
  - Mss., Op-ed: Apparently only those selected for publication, 1970 (Box 314, Folder 11-21)
  - A: Stewart Alsop, Salvadore Allende, John Akar, Mrs. Jamina Atkins (Box 314, Folder 12)
  - B: Edward C. Banfield, Edgar F. Berman, Daniel Bell, Leonard Bernstein, Nahum Bernstein, Alexander M. Bickel, Jim Bouton, Malcolm Boyd, Lord Boyd-Orr, L Brent Bozell, Jacob Brackman, Willy Brandt, Steve Brill, F. Reid Buckley, Dr. John Bunker, Anthony Burgess, Maj. Josiah Bunting III, James MacGregor Burns (Box 314, Folder 13)
  - C: William L. Cary, Lung-chu Chen, Robert Claiborne, Jerome Alan Cohen, Wilbur J. Cohen, Kenneth Clark, DR. Robert Coles, Robert Conquest, Tim Pat Coogan, Couve de Murville, Michael Crichtonb (Box 314, Folder 14)
  - D: David Dalby, Rennie Davis, William J. Dean, Jacques Decornoy, Vladimir Dedijer, Bernadette Devlin, Edward J. Dirrane, Charles Dickens, Milovan Djilas, (in English and original -- Serbo-Croatian?), Donovan, Eldridge Durbrow, Ngo Cong Due, Herman E. Daly, R. F. Delderfield, Mark Dintanfass (Box 314, Folder 15)
  - E: Anthony Eden, Paul R. Ehrlich, Julius Epstein (Box 314, Folder 16)
  - F: Bernard T, Feld, Jack Finney, Thomas Fleming, Abe Fortas, Donald M. Fraser, Victor R. Fuchs, Buckminster Fuller (Box 314, Folder 17)
  - G: John Kenneth Galbraith, Fred Gardner, Michel Garibalm Roman Gary, Nathan Glazer, Arthur J. Goldberg, Ronald L. Goldfarb, Barry M. Goldwater, Sen. Charles E. Goodell, Nadine Gordimer, Gunther Grass, Andrew Greeley, Bertram M. Gross, Ernest A. Gross (Box 314, Folder 18)
  - H: Najeeb E. Halaby, Louis J. Halle, Douglass Hallet, Morton H. Halperin, Ronald Harowy, Vincent Harding, W. Averell Harriman, James T. Harford, Tom Hayden, Shirley Hazzard, Paul Hemphill, Theodore M. Hesburgh, Sen. Ernest F. Hollings, Sidney Hook, Arthyr H. House (and Robert L. West), Chet Huntley, DR. Arnold Hutschnecker (Box 314, Folder 19)
  - I: Charles Issawi (Box 314, Folder 20)
  - J: Oliver Jackman, Jacob K. Javits, Philip C. Jessup, Gilbert Jonas, Thomas Jorling (Box 314, Folder 21)
  - K: George F. Kennan, Barbara Kerr, Theodore Kheel, Grayson Kirk, Herbert G. Klein, Dr. W. Graham Knox, Jerzy Kosinski, Joseph Kraft, Philip B. Kurland (Box 663, Folder 22)
  - L: Laurence Lader, Alexander Laing, Alf Landon, Terry Lenzner, Julius Lester, Anthony Lester, Frederic Lilge, John V. Lindsay, Mary E. Mebane (Liza), Mrs. Oswald B. Lord, Laurence E. Lucas, Gyorgy Lukacs (Box 663, Folder 23)
  - M: Priscilla McMillan, Paul D. MacLean, Tom McSlay, Thomas J. Mackell, Keith Mano, Seymour Melman, Herbert Marcuse, Charles Meyer (in English and French), Golda Meir, Mihajlo Mihajlov (original and English translation), T. B. Millar, Arthur Miller, Oskar Morgenstern, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Lewis Mumford, the ReV. F. X. Murphy (Box 663, Folder 24)
  - N: Ralph Nader, Arthur Naftalin, Joseph Natpolitan, Richard P. Nathan, Anthony Netboy, Hilary Ng'weno, Reinhold Niebuhr, Richard H. Nolte (Box 663, Folder 25)
  - O: Ned O'Gorman, Barbara Ondrasik (Box 663, Folder 26)
  - P: Joseph Papaleo, Alan Paton, Jaroslav Pelikan, S. J. Perelman, H. Ross Perot, Prince Philip, William E. Phipps, Mark Ptashne (Box 663, Folder 27)
  - R: Milton G. Rector, George E. Reedy, Charles A. Reich, Joseph Rhodes, Frank Rich, Elliot Richardson, Adm. H. G. Rickover, Robert Rivkin, J. L. Robertson, Harry Howe Ransom, Elliott Roosevelt, M. L. Rosenthal, Jerome Rosow, W. W. Rostow, Mstislav Rostropovich, J. H. Rothschild, Cardinal Roy (Box 663, Folder 28)
  - S: William Safire, Fred Saidy, Kinkazu Saionji, Paul A. Samuelson, Raymond J. Saulnier, David Schoenbrun, Alvin L. Schorr, Jonathan Schwartz, Scotus, Herbert Scoville, Glenn T. Seaborg, Carolyn See, Eric Sevareid, Frank Shakespeare, Bruno Shaw, Marshall D. Schulman, Norodom Sihanouk, Fred C. Simmons, Theodore Sorensen, Prince Souphanouvong, Jeffrey ST. John, S. Frederick Starr, Casey Stengel, Adlai E. Stevenson, III, Peter Stone, Harvey Swados, Sterling Stuckey (Box 663, Folder 29)
  - T: Telford Taylor, Studs Terkel, Barbara Tuchman, Rexford G. Tugwell.S - William Safire, Fred Saidy, Kinkazu Saionji, Paul A. Samuelson, Raymond J. Saulnier, David Schoenbrun, Alvin L. Schorr, Jonathan Schwartz, Scotus, Herbert Scoville, Glenn T. Seaborg, Carolyn See, Eric Sevareid, Frank Shakespeare, Bruno Shaw, Marshall D. Schulman, Norodom Sihanouk, Fred C. Simmons, Theodore Sorensen, Prince Souphanouvong, Jeffrey ST. John, S. Frederick Starr, Casey Stengel, Adlai E. Stevenson, III, Peter Stone, Harvey Swados, Sterling Stuckey (Box 663, Folder 30)
  - U: U Nu, Bedrich Utitz, Louis Untermeyer (Box 663, Folder 31)
  - V: Andrei Vosnesensky (Box 663, Folder 32)
  - W: Henry C. Wallich, Earl Warren, Arthur I. Waskow, Wasson, Auberon Waugh, Thomas J. Watson, Jr., J. Wreford Watson, Caspar Weinberger, Paul Weiss, Cora Weiss, Arnold Wesker, Arnold Whitridge, jerome B. Weisner, Roger Wilkins, Robert F. Williams, Stephen Wizner, LieuT. Richard W. Wooodman (Box 663, Folder 33)
  - YZ: Empty (Box 663)
  - The Long March: ChS. XXV, XXVIII, XXX, XXIX, XXVII, Miscellaneous pp., XXVI, XXIV, XXIII, X, VII, VIII -- Typescript with pencil revisions,: John Service, (Photocopy, Correspondence, index, Epilogue, Introduction ) (Box 315, Folder 1)
  - The Long March: 2 copies, Chs. XXX, XIII, XXIV - XXVIII, I - III, (Photocopy, Introduction, Epilogue ) (Box 315, Folder 2)
  - The Long March Photocopy: Chs. IV - IX, IXa, X - XII, XIV, XV, XIV, Miscellaneous pp. (270-277), chs. XVI - XXIII (Box 315, Folder 3)
  - The Long March Master I: Some pencil corrections -- Introduction, Chs. I - XV, (Photocopy ) (Box 316, Folder 4)
  - The Long March Master II: Chs. XVI - XXXI (Epilogue) (Box 316, Folder 5)
  - The Long March Miscellaneous pp., (Photocopies, Galleys, Index ) (Box 317, Folder 6)
  - The Long March: Apparently complete, (Galleys) (Box 317, Folder 7)
  - The Long March: Through Chpt 13, typescript with pencil revisions, (Photocopies, Work Sheets, Copies ) (Box 317, Folder 8)
  - The Long March I: Ch. I, 3 copies (Box 317, Folder 9)
  - The Long March II: 1 copy, marked "not edited" (Box 317, Folder 10)
  - The Long March III: 1 copy, not edited (Box 317, Folder 11)
  - The Long March IV: 1 copy, not edited (Box 317, Folder 12)
  - The Long March V: 1 copy, not edited (Box 317, Folder 13)
  - The Long March VI: 1 copy (Box 317, Folder 14)
  - The Long March VII: Empty (Box 317)
  - The Long March VIII: 4 copies, not all complete (Box 317, Folder 15)
  - The Long March IX: 1 copy, some extra pages (Box 317, Folder 16)
  - The Long March IXa: 1 copy & X corrected - empty (Box 317, Folder 17)
  - The Long March XI: Corrected - 1 copy (Box 318, Folder 18)
  - The Long March XII: Incomplete, several partial copies (Box 318, Folder 19)
  - The Long March XIII: Edited - 4 copies, 3 extra pages (Box 318, Folder 20)
  - The Long March XIV: 1 copy (Box 318, Folder 21)
  - The Long March XV: 1 copy, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 22)
  - The Long March XVI: 1 copy (Box 318, Folder 23)
  - The Long March XVII: 1 copy (Box 318, Folder 24)
  - The Long March XVIII: 1 copy, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 25)
  - The Long March XIX: 2 copies (Box 318, Folder 26)
  - The Long March XX: 1 copy (Box 318, Folder 27)
  - The Long March XXI: 1 copy, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 28)
  - The Long March XXII: Corrected, 1 copy, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 29)
  - The Long March XXIII: 2 copies, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 30)
  - The Long March XXIV: 2 copies (Box 318, Folder 31)
  - The Long March XXV: 2 copies (Box 318, Folder 32)
  - The Long March XXVI: 2 copies, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 33)
  - The Long March XXVII: 2 copies, extra pp (Box 318, Folder 34)
  - The Long March XXVIII: 2 copies, extra miscellaneous pp (Box 318, Folder 35)
  - The Long March XXIX: 2 copies (Box 318, Folder 36)
  - The Long March XXX: 2 copies, miscellaneous extra pp (Box 318, Folder 37)
  - The Long March XXXI: 1 copy, miscellaneous extra pp (Box 318, Folder 38)
  - Soviet Union, American Exposition: Mostly 8 x 10, b&w -- Nixon trip, 1959, (Photographs ) (Box 319)
  - Balkan Trip: Yugoslavia, Czech, Albania, Rumania, Hungary, Poland, 1957, (Photographs ) (Box 320, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Russian: Unclear which photos the typed pages refer to, (Photographs, Index) (Box 320, Folder 2)
  - From Black Night, White Snow, (Photographs ) (Box 320, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Salisbury: Pictures with Bobby/RFK, with Nixon 1968, Roxbury, 1964, (Photographs, Proof Sheets, Negatives ) (Box 320, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Salisbury, (Photographs ) (Box 320, Folder 5)
  - Contacts: Mostly Russian, 1967, (Photographs, Contact Sheets ) (Box 320, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets, (Photographs) (Box 320, Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union, 1967, (Photographs ) (Box 320, Folder 8)
  - Classic Japanese Women & 2 other art color, (Photographs Photos ) (Box 320, Folder 9)
  - Around China, Moscow, Hanoi, Sikkim, Good CYS: Includes some negatives, 1966-1967, (Photographs ) (Box 320, Folder 10)
  - Russia [Photographs]: Ipatiev House and Leningrad (Box 321, Folder 11)
  - Vietnam: Personal Salisbury, (Photographs) (Box 321, Folder 12)
  - Ukraine: 715-798 -- Mostly in envelopes, numbered, (Photographs Small Pictures ) (Box 321, Folder 13)
  - Datcha: Negatives in envelopes, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 14)
  - Samarkand, Kazak, Bokhara: Negatives in envelopes, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 15)
  - Bolshoi Ballet, (Photographs Contact Sheet, Negatives ) (Box 321, Folder 16)
  - AgFair: Negatives in envelopes, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 17)
  - Gorky Park: Negatives and small prints, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 18)
  - Yakustk, Chita, Khabarovsk: Photos in envelopes with 2 pp. of captions, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 19)
  - Barnaul, (Photographs Negatives, Contact Sheets ) (Box 321, Folder 20)
  - Stalinabad, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 21)
  - Volga: Negatives and small pictures in labelled envelopes, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 22)
  - Birobijan, (Photographs ) (Box 321, Folder 23)
  - Negatives, Snapshots, Boxes of Slides: Some labelled on back, (Photographs) (Box 322)
  - Salisbury [By year], 1944-1990 (Box 323, Folder 1)
  - Robert A. D. Ford Our Man in Moscow: A Diplomat's Reflections on the Soviet Union from Stalin to Brezhnev: University of Toronto Press, 1989, (Galleys ) (Box 323, Folder 2)
  - Connecticutt, (26 pages) (Box 323, Folder 3)
  - Shelves Extra Copy -- Miscellaneous, 1973-86 -- 8 x 10, b&amp -- w Salisbury with Nixon, Salisbury with George Kennan, Salisbury with unidentified others, 1963-1990 (Box 323, Folder 4)
  - Russia Soviet Union: Some New York Times -- See Carton 18, ca.1954, (Photo, Correspondence, Captions ) (Box 323, Folder 5)
  - Salisbury Introductions Series from German with translations -- Working paper of Osteuropa-Institut, Munchen: Freey Litton, Otto Brauns fruhes Wirken in China, apparently related to German news, ca. 1928 (Box 324, Folder 6)
  - Jan Myrdal A Chinese Village 20 Years Later: Misgivings, (Letter, Photocopy, Report, Mss., Notes ) (Box 324, Folder 7)
  - Heroes of My Time: With Salisbury to Romey -- Mss. possibly incomplete., Sept 8, 1992, (Letter, Mss. ) (Box 324, Folder 8)
  - Heroes, (Reviews ) (Box 324, Folder 9)
  - Interview, Book, Notes, Reviews: re Solzhenitsyn, Soong Chingling, Soong Meiling, Chiang Ching, etc (Box 324, Folder 10)
  - The Long March w/ John Service: re editing & spelling of Chinese names, etc. -- Photocopied pp. from book -- ChS. 1-22, possible duplicate and missing pp -- Mss, (Correspondence ) (Box 325, Folder 1)
  - The Long March Bibliography: Miscellaneous ms pp - not in order -- Complete mss. w/ pencil revisions (30 ChS.) - some duplication (Box 326, Folder 2)
  - The Long March Replacement Sheets: Mss. and galley pp. - some duplication (Box 326, Folder 3)
  - The Long March IX: 3 copies of CH. IX, pp. 152-170-1/2 (Box 327, Folder 4)
  - The Long March X: 6 copies CH. 1 (pp. 1-20, w/ title page) (Box 327, Folder 5)
  - The Long March Photocopies: Chapters. 1-17, 9-10 (duplicate), 18-29 -- Miscellaneous pp. - out of order, some stapled together (Box 327, Folder 6)
  - The Long March Photocopies: Substitute pages and original requiem, Chapter 30 -- Miscellaneous pp. w/corrections -- Note re call from Voznesensky, Feb 27, 1983 (Box 328, Folder 7)
  - The Long March Retyped Pages: Miscellaneous pp. w/pencil editing, some stuck together (Box 328, Folder 8)
  - Travels Around America: Including Hunter Thompson, David Harris, Charles Reich (s, 1975), Sinclair Lewis, Tocqueville, Trollope (research), on Hiram, (Interview, Notes, Research ) (Box 329, Folder 1)
  - Travel: North Korea Trip: In English and Korean, 1972, (Pamphlets, Newspapers, Clips, Photos, Dispatches ) (Box 329, Folder 2)
  - Travel Around America, 1975 (Box 330, Folder 4)
  - Travel: Mikoyan, Anastas Trip: 4 steno notebooks, some loose pp. of notes, 1959, (Original Notebooks ) (Box 330, Folder 5)
  - Travel: Khrushchev Trip: 3 steno notebooks, 1959, (Notebooks ) (Box 330, Folder 6)
  - Travel: Iran, Afghanistan, USSR, 1961-1962, (Notebooks, Dispatches, Notes, Photos ) (Box 330, Folder 7)
  - Travel: Khrushchev (Personal): re Khrushchev US trip, 1959-1960, (Notebooks, Notes, Dispatches ) (Box 330, Folder 8)
  - XV Dartmouth Conference, 1986, (Notebook ) (Box 330)
  - Transportation I: -- Printed and mss. articles re Salisbury New York Times series on urban transportation -- Mss of Salisbury series, 1958-1959 (Box 331, Folder 1)
  - Transportation II (Box 331, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Transportation Series, (Mss., Clippings, Series Reprints ) (Box 331, Folder 3)
  - Transportation Transportation Series, (2 Booklets, 1 Steno Notebook ) (Box 331)
  - Transportation San Francisco Bay Area Rapid Transit Commission to the California State Legislature, Dec, 1957, (Report ) (Box 332)
  - BX: Baton Rouge re Civil Rights, Southern University (Box 332, Folder 4)
  - Birmingham: 5th Circuit Court for Times and Salisbury, 1961-1965 (Box 332, Folder 5)
  - Birmingham Correppondence I: To and from Salisbury.: Material re Inter-Citizens Committee, 1960-1962, (Letters ) (Box 332, Folder 6)
  - BX: Correspondence II, Nashville (Box 332, Folder 7)
  - Birmingham Correspondence III: Includes series of "Documents on Human Rights in Alabama", (Correspondence ) (Box 333, Folder 9)
  - Birmingham: -- Violence in NY Quotes Salisbury -- Including more on Human Rights in Alabama, 1963-1964 (Box 333, Folder 10)
  - BX: -- Embrey Material from Birmingham Chamber of Commerce Miscellaneous LBJ, Wallace and from Eugene (Bull) Connor, 1964-1979 (Box 333, Folder 11)
  - A Time to Speak: Salisbury notes -- Photocopy of "A Time to Speak", by Charles Morgan, Jr., with letter to Salisbury, 1/11/79 -- Some pages out of sequence., 1964 (Box 333, Folder 12)
  - Birmingham, 1962-1963 (Box 333, Folder 13)
  - Birmingham Pamphlets, Correspondence, Notes, Court Documents: Incl. Eugene Cononr V. New York Times and Salisbury: Outline for student paper re Birmingham, 1960-1981 (Box 333, Folder 14)
  - Birmingham: Trial Press Coverage, 1960-1964 (Box 333, Folder 15)
  - Birmingham My Fellow Clergymen: Martin L. King from Birmingham City Jail, 1963, (Letter ) (Box 333, Folder 16)
  - Robert Gaines Corley Birmingham The Quest for Racial Harmiony: Race Relations in Birmingham, Alabama, 1947-1963: Incomplete -- Department of History, University of Virginia (Chs. 1-4) -- See also folder 23, 1979, (Mss. ) (Box 334, Folder 17)
  - Engel, David Lowe Birmingham: Bessemer Indictment (Box 334, Folder 18)
  - Allen University Sit-Ins, Raleigh NC; Columbia SC, 1959-1960 (Box 334, Folder 19)
  - Birmingham Trial: -- Loeb evidence given by Salisbury -- Other material related to court case, including offers to vouch for accuracy of Salisbury story -- More documents on human rights in Alabama (Box 334, Folder 20)
  - Birmingham: Trial - Evidence (Box 334, Folder 21)
  - Birmingham Birmingham, Nashville Baton Rouge Raleigh Columbia SC, (Clips, Printed Newspaper Clips ) (Box 334, Folder 22)
  - Birmingham Robert Corley - II: Continuation from folder 17, (Book, PhD Thesis ) (Box 334, Folder 23)
  - Birmingham Key Notes, Reconstructions, Telegrams, Original Typed Stories, Corrections, Editing (Box 334, Folder 24)
  - Michael Rozanov Soviet Union: -- Letter, Mss.: In Russian -- Black folder., Feb 23, 1983 (Box 335, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Union: Including in French and Russian -- Radio Liberty, Text of Solzhenitsyn speech 7/9/75 (in English), 1974-1976 (Box 335, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union: -- Leningrad - Soviet Material for The 900 Days, (Poetry, Newspapers, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 336, Folder 2)
  - Soviet Union: -- Miscellaneous, 1958-1961, (RFE Material, Russian Newspapers, Embassy Press Releases ) (Box 336, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet Newspapers: Sovietskaya Kultura, Literaturnaya Gazeta, Literatura i Zhizn, Komsomolskaya Pravda, 1959 (Box 337, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Union: Literary and Samizdat Khrushchev Funeral Samizdart Material, 1971-1972 (Box 337, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Union: -- General RFE/RL, 1977, (Research Materials ) (Box 337, Folder 7)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: Introduction, pp. 1-399, 1969 (Box 338, Folder 1)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: pp. 400-804 (Box 338, Folder 2)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: pp. 805 - 1193 (end) (Box 338, Folder 3)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: Journals duplicate copy, to pp. 303 (Box 339, Folder 4)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: Duplicate, pp. 304-542 (Box 339, Folder 5)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: Duplicate, pp. 678-1002 (Box 339, Folder 6)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Wartime Journals: Duplicate, pp. 1008-1193 (Box 339, Folder 7)
  - Early, Chicago, 1930s & 1940s, (Clips, 2 Brown Scrapbooks w/ Newspaper Clippings ) (Box 340)
  - Large Embossed Scrapbook: w/ note from Janet. REMOVED: oversized scrapbook. (Box 341)
  - Edward Jay Epstein, Inquest and Mark Lane, Rush to Judgement, (Review ) (Box 342, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Correspondence re. Oswald, Warren, etc. (Box 342, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy Assassination: -- Oswald Case [removed 2 books: Robert J. Donovan, The Assassins, Popular Library (Pb), 1964 -- Joachim Joesten, Oswald: Assassin or Fall Guy? (NY: Marzani -- and Munsell), 1964 -- Salisbury introduction to Warren Commission - readers proof and copies (Box 342, Folder 5)
  - JFK re-Examination: Peter Kihss, Warren Wrap-up, 52 pp., Nov-Dec 1966, (Memo, Mss. ) (Box 342, Folder 6)
  - Kihss-Warren I: Multiple copies or versions -- Expanded version of part of #6, (Mss. ) (Box 342, Folder 7)
  - Kihss-Warren II: Continuation of #7, (Typescript w/ Ink Revisions, Carbons Attached ) (Box 342, Folder 8)
  - Kihss-Warren III: Similar to #8, (w/ Memo ) (Box 342, Folder 9)
  - Kihss-Warren IV: Similar to 7 and 8 (Box 342, Folder 10)
  - Kihss-Warren V: As above, fewer versions (Box 342, Folder 11)
  - Kennedy: No V. 1-7, 1960 (Box 343, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Assassination: -- Data to Salisbury at New York Times (Box 343, Folder 3)
  - China: 100 Years, (Captions, Publicity Material, Photo, Correspondence, Notes ) (Box 343, Folder 12)
  - China in Revolution: 324 pp., (Mss. ) (Box 343, Folder 13)
  - China: Incomplete copy, (Mss. ) (Box 343, Folder 14)
  - China: 237 pp. -- Possibly different version from #14, (Mss. ) (Box 344, Folder 15)
  - China: Photocopied sample pages from publisher, Miscellaneous chapters and pages - some duplication and/or different versions, (Mss. ) (Box 344, Folder 16)
  - China: Miscellaneous chapters and pages, (Mss. ) (Box 344, Folder 17)
  - China: pp. 85-186 (photocopied, with pencil revisions), some out of order, (Mss. ) (Box 344, Folder 18)
  - China: Chapters X - XII (pp. 187-241) - photocopied pages, corrected before copying, (Mss. ) (Box 344, Folder 19)
  - China in Revolution: Original typescript with pencil corrections (possibly some missing pages) -- Miscellaneous duplicate pages (photocopied) (Box 344, Folder 20)
  - A Time Of Change: Chapters I - X. Photocopies, with notes from Charlotte Curtis -- Some marginal comments, probably also from Curtis., (Mss. ) (Box 345, Folder 1)
  - A Time Of Change: Chapters (photocopies). Chapters. IV, V, VII, VIII (4 copies), IX, X, XII (2 copies), XIII, XVII (3 copies), XIX, XX (2 copies), XXIV - XXX, (Mss. ) (Box 345, Folder 2)
  - A Time Of Change: Miscellaneous chapters. Typescript with pencil corrections, inserts (some duplicates) -- Jacket copy, author's introduction, (Mss., Notes ) (Box 346, Folder 3)
  - A Time Of Change: Chapters. Miscellaneous, multiple versions -- Salisbury letters to Mike and Charlotte Curtis, (Mss. ) (Box 346, Folder 4)
  - A Time Of Change: Miscellaneous pp. Typescript with pencil corrections -- Some handwritten (Box 346, Folder 5)
  - A Time Of Change: Mostly complete mss. clean copy, pp. 6-390 (end) (Box 347, Folder 6)
  - A Time Of Change: Some pp. missing, (Page Proofs ) (Box 347, Folder 7)
  - A Time Of Change: Duplicate, some missing pp, (Page Proofs ) (Box 347, Folder 8)
  - A Time Of Change, (Jacket Design, Index, Proofs, Letter ) (Box 347, Folder 9)
  - Text of Speech by Tito: re Hungary, Suez, Nov 16, 1956 (Box 348, Folder 1)
  - Communists: Some re. Sino-Soviet dispute, ca. 1960s (Box 348, Folder 2)
  - Sulzberger, Iphigene Ochs Re death of Iphigene Ochs Sulzberger 2/26/90 -- To Salisbury from David Halberstam, 1960 -- To Salisbury from Seymour Topping, 1961, 1990-1992 (Box 348, Folder 3)
  - New York Times, 1991-1992 (Box 348, Folder 4)
  - New York Times, 1957-90 (Box 348, Folder 5)
  - Sulzberger, C. L. Correspondence, 1954-91 (Box 348, Folder 6)
  - Sulzberger, Iphigene Ochs Memorial Service for, 1961-90 (Box 348, Folder 7)
  - China and Russia: -- Re US-Soviet and US-Chinese Writers' Conferences -- Some re Salisbury, China: 100 Years of Revolution -- Francine du Plessix Gray, 1983-1985 (Box 349, Folder 8)
  - Dick/ David China: -- 100 Years of Revolution, (Reviews ) (Box 349, Folder 9)
  - Andropov, Yuri RFE/RL In English, Russian, and French (Box 349, Folder 10)
  - Andropov, Yuri RFE/RL (Box 349, Folder 11)
  - Andropov, Yuri Contents as above (Box 349, Folder 12)
  - Russia: George Polk Awards, 1955-67 (Box 349, Folder 13)
  - Books: Papers removed. Books shelved separately. (Box 349, Folder 14-27)
  - Perry Link Evening Chats in Beijing: Probing China's Predicament: Norton, 1992 - uncorrected proof (Box 349, Folder 14)
  - A. I. Cherpanov Zapiski Voennogo Covetnika v Kitae, 1994-1995 (Box 349, Folder 15)
  - Petr Ryss Russkii Opyt, 1976-1977 (Box 349, Folder 16)
  - G. K. Kozlov V Lesakh Karelii, 1998-1999 (Box 349, Folder 17)
  - P. I. Kulakov S Boyami Vzyatye Vysoty: P. 3 (Box 349, Folder 18)
  - Z. V. Toikka Skvoz Grozovye Gody: Inside cover (Box 349, Folder 19)
  - Boevye Vympela and Onego: 2 copies - papers wrapped around (Box 349, Folder 20)
  - G. K. Kuprianov Ot Barentseva Morya do Ladogi: End (Box 349, Folder 21)
  - O. TIkhonov Operatsiya v Zone "Vakuum": Beginning (Box 349, Folder 22)
  - V Groznye Gody: Beginning (Box 349, Folder 23)
  - A. A. Sokolov V Bessmennom Dozore (Box 349, Folder 24)
  - G. A. Gerasimov Partizanskie Kilometry: Piece of envelope folded over from cover -- Larger paper, pp. 150-1 (Box 349, Folder 25)
  - Gromyko: P. 102-3, (Memoirs ) (Box 349, Folder 26)